Guide to the Dimension Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Dimension records
1962-2007
1968-1994
YCGL MSS 29
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
75.4
(85 boxes) + 1 broadside, 1 package, 1 roll
The Dimension Records document the creation and publication of Dimension by its founder and editor, A. Leslie Willson. The collection contains subject files concerning authors and translators of German literature; drafts of writings and translations published in Dimension; drafts and proofs for Dimension, including most issues in volumes 1-19 and several special issues; subscription and other business records for Dimension; writings and translations of A. Leslie Willson; a small amount of records relating to Willson's work at the University of Texas and in professional organizations; photographs and slides of German authors and artists and their work; drawings and prints by German artists; and audio and audiovisual recordings, including Gruppe 47 conferences, author readings, radio plays, lectures, and interviews. Materials pertaining to Dimension document its history and funding; publication of authors, artists, and translators; and production of individual issues. Also present are correspondence, writings, photographs, and sound recordings concerning Willson's broader professional and personal relationships with German authors and academic colleagues. The collection is a resource for the study of German literature, art, and literary translation during the 1960s-1990s, as well as the teaching of German literature in American universities during the same period.
Dimension (Austin, Tex.)
Willson, A. Leslie (Amos Leslie), 1923-2007
Bender, Hans, 1919-
Bichsel, Peter, 1935-
Grass, Günter, 1927-2015
Jandl, Ernst, 1925-2000
Köpf, Gerhard, 1948-
Kunert, Günter, 1929-
Lenz, Siegfried, 1926-2014
Mayröcker, Friederike, 1924-
Wohmann, Gabriele, 1932-2015
Wolf, Christa, 1929-2011
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of A. Leslie Willson, 1996-2008. Gift of Juliet Willson Jimenez, Brian L. Willson, and Kevin R. Willson, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 68-69 (Teaching Materials): Restricted until 2085. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 71-80 (Audiovisual Materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 81 (computer disks): ‡a Restricted fragile material. Reference copies are available for disks 4-6 and 8-11; reference copies for disks 1-3, 7, and 12-18 may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Dimension
Dimension: Contemporary German Arts and Letters was a bilingual German/English literary journal edited by A. Leslie Willson, professor of Germanic Studies at the University of Texas at Austin. Founded by Willson in 1968, Dimension was published through 1994 in a total of more than eighty regular and special issues. Willson stated that the goals of the journal were to improve the quality of translation and redress the time lag between the appearance of new literary writing in German and its availibility to English readers. Dimension published poems, plays, essays, short stories, radio plays, excerpts from novels, and drawings by hundreds of German-language authors and artists, including Peter Bichsel, Günter Grass, Gerhard Köpf, Günter Kunert, Siegfried Lenz, Ernst Jandl, Friederike Mayröcker, Gabriele Wohamnn, and Christa Wolf. Through publication of well-known authors, discovery of new authors, and collaboration between authors, translators, and editors, Dimension came to be regarded internationally as an influential forum for contemporary arts and letters.
Dimension was funded by the University of Texas at Austin from its inception in 1968 through 1975. Funding was increasingly problematic after this, and when Willson's term as chairman of the University's German Department ended in 1980, he continued publication of Dimension without clerical or editorial support. Volumes 1-15:1 were designed and produced by the University of Texas Press at Austin. Starting with volume 15:2, Willson designed and produced the journal himself on an Apple computer. Dimension²: Contemporary German-language Literature, edited by Ingo R. Stoehr, began publication in 1994, continuing the format of the original journal.
A. Leslie Willson
A. (Amos) Leslie Willson (1923-2007), professor of German, author, editor, and translator, was born in Texas, studied journalism and German at the University of Texas at Austin, and earned a Ph.D. from Yale University in 1954. He was a member of the German Department faculty at the University of Texas at Austin, 1955-1961 and 1966-1992, and was emeritus professor of Germanic Languages, 1992-2007.
Willson's translations include novels by Michael Krüger ( The Man in the Tower and Himmelfarb ), Gerhard Köpf ( There is no Borges; Papa's Suitcase; Innerfar; Bluff, or The Southern Cross; Way to Eden; Nurmi, or The Journey to the Trout; and Piranesi's Dream ), and Ulla Berkéwicz ( Angels are Black and White ), and Hermann Kurzke's Thomas Mann: Life as a Work of Art. In addition to founding and editing Dimension, his work as an editor included several volumes of The German Library (Continuum Press). Willson co-founded the American Literary Translators Association in 1979 and was its first president. He served as president of the American Translators Association from 1991 to 1993.
Scope and Contents
The Dimension Records document the creation and publication of Dimension by its founder and editor, A. Leslie Willson. The collection contains subject files concerning authors and translators of German literature; drafts of writings and translations published in Dimension; drafts and proofs for Dimension, including most issues in volumes 1-19 and several special issues; subscription and other business records for Dimension; writings and translations of A. Leslie Willson; a small amount of records relating to Willson's work at the University of Texas and in professional organizations; photographs and slides of German authors and artists and their work; drawings and prints by German artists; and audio and audiovisual recordings, including Gruppe 47 conferences, author readings, radio plays, lectures, and interviews. Materials pertaining to Dimension document its history and funding; publication of authors, artists, and translators; and production of individual issues. Also present are correspondence, writings, photographs, and sound recordings concerning Willson's broader professional and personal relationships with German authors and academic colleagues. The collection is a resource for the study of German literature, art, and literary translation during the 1960s-1990s, as well as the teaching of German literature in American universities during the same period.
Arrangement
Organized into seven series: I. Subject Files. II. Dimension Production Materials. III. Dimension Business Records. IV. Writings. V. Personal Papers of A. Leslie Willson. VI. Graphic Materials. VII. Audiovisual Materials.
Dimension (Austin, Tex.); Art, German -- 20th Century; Artists -- Germany -- 20th Century; Authors, German -- 20th Century; German literature -- 20th Century; German literature -- Translations into English; Little magazines; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Radio plays, German; Audiotapes; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Drawings (visual works); Electronic documents; Interviews; Lectures; Long-playing records; Photographic prints; Posters; Prints (Visual works); Slides (photographs); Videotapes; Bender, Hans, 1919-; Bichsel, Peter, 1935-; Grass, Günter, 1927-2015; Jandl, Ernst, 1925-2000; Köpf, Gerhard, 1948-; Kunert, Günter, 1929-; Lenz, Siegfried, 1926-2014; Mayröcker, Friederike, 1924-; Willson, A. Leslie (Amos Leslie), 1923-2007; Willson, Jeanne; Wohmann, Gabriele, 1932-2015; Wolf, Christa, 1929-2011; American Literary Translators Association; American Translators Association; Gruppe 47 (Germany); University of Texas at Austin. Department of Germanic Languages
- Subject Files, Series I; 31; (31 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I, Subject Files, is organized into five subseries: Subject Files, circa 1962-1982; Subject Files, circa 1966-1988; Subject Files, 1970s; Other Subject Files; and Unsorted Subject Files. All subseries except Unsorted Subject Files are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  Scope and Contents
  Most subjects are authors, translators, or other colleagues associated with the production of Dimension. A few files of Dimension business records are present. Files typically contain correspondence with A. Leslie Willson, drafts of writings, and related printed material. The first three subseries are original file groups created by Willson; these are followed by additional files sorted by name and unsorted files. Original file groups date mostly circa 1962-1980, after which filing systems apparently were discontinued, probably due to lack of clerical assistance for the production of Dimension. Subject content and date spans therefore overlap among original file groups and later materials.
  - Subject Files, circa 1962-1982
    Most files are for translators, with some for literary agents and editorial associates. Many files are for American colleagues and contain materials relating to academic activity.
    - A-Hu (Box 1)
    - Hu-Sh (Box 2)
    - Sm -Z (Box 3)
    - Dimension business records (Box 3)
  - Subject Files, circa 1966-1988
    Most files are for authors, with some for artists, translators, and other colleagues. Many files consist mainly or entirely of clippings and other printed material. Names are followed by date spans of materials; most materials date predominantly from the 1970s, reflecting Willson's work in mapping the German literary scene and solicitation of contributions for Dimension during that period.
    Empty folders for the following names were discarded: Sophie Brandes, Walter Mathias Diggelmann, Roderick Feldes, Iring Fetscher, Wolfgang Fienhold, Wolfgang Gabel, Ulrich Greiner, Peter Grosz, Herbert Günter, Franz Haderer, Johannes Hübner, Paul Gerhard Hübsch, Lothar Klünner, Klaus Konjetzky; Hans Mans, Anneliese Meinert, Gina Ruck Pauquet, Ilse Pracht-Fitzell, Gerd Sonntag.
    - A-Biel (Box 3)
    - Bien-Er (Box 4)
      Includes:
      Buch, Hans Christoph (1972-1987)
      Canetti, Elias (1968-1972)
      Domin, Hilde (1970s)
      Eich, Günter (1972)
      Enzensberger, Hans Magnus (1967-1986; about Eremiten-Presse)
    - Er-Hec (Box 5)
      Fichte, Hubert (1968-1978)
      Flora, Paul (1968-1969)
      Frisch, Max (1971)
      Frischmuth, Barbara (1970-1975)
      Fuchs, Günter Bruno (1970)
      Grün, Max von der (1969-1980)
      Gruppe 47
      Hacks, Peter (1969-1974)
      Handke, Peter (1967)
      Härtling, Peter (1968-1972)
    - Hei-Kro (Box 6)
      Hildesheimer, Wolfgang (1967-1978)
      Hochhuth, Rolf (1970)
      Höllerer, Walter (1968-1985)
      Ivask, Ivar (1968-1987)
      Jandl, Ernst (1968-1987)
      Johnson, Uwe (1967-1972)
      Kahn, Lisa
      Kaschnitz, Maria Luise (1967)
      Krolow, Karl (1968-1973)
    - Kru-Ree (Box 7)
      Kunert, Günter (with literary texts, a clipping file, and original photographs of Kunert)
      Lenz, Siegfried (1967-1987)
      Lettau, Reinhard (1967-1969)
      Lysohorsky, Ondra (1973-1976)
      Müller, Heiner (1975)
      Muschg, Adolf (1977)
      Nossack, Hans Erich (1968)
      Otto, Hans-Peter (1976; photographs of a literary conference, probably in Austin)
      Pabisch, Peter (1978-1980)
      Piontek, Heinz (1968-1977)
      Rathenow, Lutz (1976-1981; with several texts)
    - Reg-Wall (Box 8)
      Reinig, Christa (1969-1987)
      Richter, Hans Werner (1968-1987)
      Rühmkorf, Peter (1967-1987)
      Unseld, Siegfried (1976-1982)
      Verlag Klaus Wagenbach (1969-1973)
      Viebahn, Fred (1970-1985)
      Vormweg, Heinrich (1968-1976)
    - Wals-Z (Box 9)
      Walser, Martin (1966-1987)
      Weiss, Peter (1968-1978)
      Weissenborn, Theodor (1970-1980)
      Wellershoff, Dieter (1967-1987)
      Weyrauch, Wolfgang (1967-1980)
      Wohmann, Gabriele (1967-1987)
      Wolf, Christa (1974)
      Wondratschek, Wolf (1968-1971)
    - " Dimension correspondence (closed)", 1968-1972 (Box 9)
  - Subject Files, 1970s
    Most files concern authors and translators whose work was published in Dimension or was considered for publication, possibly with some unsolicited contributions. Contents consist of German texts, manuscript or photocopy; drafts or printer's copies of translations; and some Dimension offprints and other clippings. These files contain almost no correspondence.
    - B-Cha (Box 9)
    - Che-Ga (Box 10)
    - Ge-Hedges (Box 11)
      Geerk, Frank (apparently early unpublished novel titled "Plastic, eine Apokalypse")
      Kunert, Günter ("Gast aus England," photocopy of corrected typescript; poems; and short prose texts with translations)
    - Hein-Lins (Box 12)
    - Loet-O'Hearn (Box 13)
      Mechtel, Angelika (1970s; correspondence)
      Meckel, Christoph (contains informal original art)
      Müller, Heiner (contains adaptation of Feydor Gladkov's play "Zement," English translation, possibly unpublished)
    - Okopenko-Rich (Box 14)
      Piontek, Heinz
      Read, Ralph
      Reinfrank, Arno
      Reinig, Christa
    - Rip-Spe (Box 15)
      Rühmkorf, Peter
      Salinger, Herman
      Schnetz, Peter
      Seyppel, Joachim
      Sperr, Martin
    - Spr-Waniek (Box 16)
      Spycher, Peter
      Vormweg, Heinrich
      Walser, Martin
    - Ward-Willson (Box 17)
      Ward, David
      Viebahn, Fred
      Weyrauch, Wolfgang
      Willson, A. Leslie
    - Wirth-Zw (Box 18)
      Wohmann, Gabriele
      Wolf, Christa (contains "Blichwechsel," story, carbon typescript)
    - "Fee schedule" (Box 18)
  - Other Subject Files
    These files are a partial organization of materials left unsorted by Willson. More materials relating to the same names may be found in remaining unsorted files. Contents include drafts and proofs of works in progress, translations, and correspondence.
    - Aichinger, Ilse (Box 18)
    - Amery, Carl (Box 18)
      Das Königsprojekt, excerpt in English translation
    - Andres, Dorothee (Box 18)
    - Arnold, Heinz Ludwig (Box 18)
    - Augustin Michael (Box 18)
      Frau Sebald...
    - Becker, Jurek (Box 18)
    - Becker, Jürgen (Box 18)
    - Becker, Uli (Box 18)
    - Bender, Hans (Box 18)
    - Berkewicz, Ulla (Box 18)
    - Bernhard, Thomas (Box 18)
      The Ignorant and the Mad
    - Bienek, Horst (Box 18)
    - Böll, Heinrich (Box 18)
    - Bonner-Saroff, Timothy A. (Box 18)
    - Borchert, Wolfgang (Box 18)
      The Man Outside, translated by David Porter and A. Leslie Willson
    - Borovski, Conrad (Box 18)
    - Braendle, Christoph (Box 18)
    - Buch, Hans Christoph (Box 18)
    - Buselmeier, Michael (Box 19)
    - Chappel, Allen H. (Box 19)
    - Dean, Jay Douglas (Box 19)
    - Da Costa, Bernard (Box 19)
      Pat and Sarah
    - Delius, Friedrich Christian (Box 19)
    - Denton, Eric (Box 19)
    - Dittberner, Hugo (Box 19)
    - Domin, Hilde (Box 19)
    - Drewitz, Ingeborg (Box 19)
    - Eckart, Gabriele (Box 19)
    - Enzensberger, Hans Magnus (Box 19)
    - Eremiten Presse (Box 19)
    - Exner, Richard (Box 19)
    - Fels, Ludwig (Box 19)
    - Fichte, Hubert (Box 19)
    - Frank, Karlhans (Box 19)
    - Fries, Fritz Rudolf (Box 19)
    - Frischmuth, Barbara (Box 19)
      Untime
    - Fritz, Walter Helmut (Box 19)
    - Fröhlich, Hans J. (Box 19)
    - Fühmann, Franz (Box 19)
      Spiegelgeschichte, translated by Esther E. Enns
    - Geerk, Frank (Box 19)
    - Geiser, Cristoph (Box 19)
    - Goethe-Institut Houston (Box 19)
    - Goy, Erwin (Box 19)
    - Graf, Karin (Box 19)
    - Grass, Günter (Box 19)
      Includes interview material
    - Grass, Günter (Box 20)
    - GRIPS Theater (Box 20)
      Eine linke Geschichte
    - Gruppe 47 (Box 20)
    - Grzimek, Martin (Box 20)
    - Handke, Peter (Box 20)
    - Haufs, Rolf (Box 20)
    - Harig, Ludwig (Box 20)
    - Heckmann, Herbert (Box 20)
    - Hegewald, Wolfgang (Box 20)
    - Hillebrand, Bruno and Dorothee (Box 20)
    - Hilscher, Eberhard (Box 20)
    - Höllerer, Walter (Box 20)
    - Hübner, Uwe (Box 20)
      Poems and other writings in German, typescript
    - Hunt, Irmgard Elsner (Box 20)
    - Irving, John (Box 20)
    - Ivask, Ivar and Astrid (Box 20)
    - Jandl, Ernst (Box 20)
    - Jandl, Ernst and Mayröcker, Friederike (Box 20)
    - Johansen, Hanna (Box 20)
    - Johnson, Uwe (Box 20)
      Includes reading notes and A. Leslie Willson's interview with Johnson
    - Kahn, Lisa (Box 21)
    - Kirsch, Sarah (Box 21)
      Poems, translated by Helmbrecht Breinig and Kevin Power
    - Kirsten, Wulf (Box 21)
    - König, Barbara (Box 21)
    - Kolbe, Uwe (Box 21)
      Bornholm II, translated by Crocker Coulson, photocopy and typescripts of translation
    - Köpf, Gerhard, 1992-1996 (Box 21)
      Includes drafts of essays and stories by Köpf; reviews, newspaper articles, announcements, and advertisements related to Köpf's books; secondary correspondence with George Braziller, Köpf's American publisher; and material relating to translations of Köpf's writings by A. Leslie Willson
    - Köpf, Gerhard (Box 22)
    - Kortmann, Christian (Box 22)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard (Box 22)
    - Krier, Jean (Box 22)
    - Kroliczak, Hans (Box 22)
    - Krüger, Michael (Box 22)
    - Kuhner, Herbert (Box 22)
    - Kunert, Günter (Box 23)
      Includes photographs and secondary correspondence
    - Kunze, Rainer (Box 23)
    - Kurzke, Hermann (Box 23)
    - Lenz, Ernst (Box 23)
    - Loetscher, Hugo (Box 23)
    - Mayröcker, Friederike (Box 23)
    - Meckel, Cristoph (Box 23)
    - Mitchell, Breon (Box 23)
    - Nadolny, Sten (Box 23)
    - New Directions Publishing Corporation (Box 23)
    - Nitschke, Wolfgang (Box 23)
    - Ortheil, Hanns-Josef (Box 23)
    - Pabisch, Peter K. (Box 23)
    - Pastior, Oskar (Box 23)
    - Pedretti, Erika (Box 23)
    - Picard, Walter (Box 23)
    - Piontek, Heinz (Box 23)
    - Pittermann, Erwein (Box 23)
    - Praesent, Angela (Box 23)
      Au contraire
    - Radio plays (Box 23)
      Typescripts, photocopies, and West German Radio copyright copies
      Includes plays by Alfred Andersch, Hans Magnus Enzensberger, Kieseritzky, Dieter Kühn, Harald Mueller, Hannelies Taschaum, Theodor Weissenborn, and Urs Widmer
    - Rathenow, Lutz (Box 23)
    - Read, Ralph (Box 23)
    - Rechenberg, Gerda (Box 23)
      Writings and dossier
    - Reinfrank, Arno (Box 23)
    - Richter, Hans Werner (Box 23)
    - Rodden, Warrick (Box 23)
    - Rosendorfer, Herbert (Box 23)
    - Rosenlöcher, Thomas (Box 23)
    - Salinger, Herman and Marion (Box 23)
    - Schädlich, Hans Joachim (Box 24)
    - Schneider, Peter (Box 24)
    - Söllner, Werner (Box 24)
    - Stadler, Arnold (Box 24)
    - Stoehr, Ingo Roland (Box 24)
      Includes secondary correspondence
    - Suhrkamp Verlag (Box 24)
      Includes correspondence of Siegfried Unseld, Ulla Berkewicz, and others
    - Thaland, Rijn (Box 24)
      Dossier of poems
    - Török, Imre (Box 24)
    - Viebahn, Fred, and Rita Dove (Box 24)
    - Walser, Martin (Box 24)
    - Ward, David (Box 24)
    - Ward, Ruth (Box 24)
    - Wecker, Christoph (Box 24)
    - Wellershoff, Dieter (Box 24)
    - Wetzels, Walter (University of Texas at Austin German Department) (Box 24)
    - Weyrauch, Wolfgang and Margot (Box 24)
    - Widmer, Alexander (Box 24)
      Poems
    - Willson, Jeanne and Brian (Box 24)
    - Wohmann, Gabriele (Box 24)
    - Wolff, Helen, and Helen and Kurt Wolff Books (Box 24)
    - Wondratschek, Wolf (Box 24)
    - Wühr, Paul (Box 24)
    - Zauner, Hansjörg (Box 24)
    - Zoderer, Joseph (Box 24)
    - Zohn, Harry (Box 24)
    - Zrenner, Walter (Box 24)
      Poems and other writings
    - Zwillinger, Frank G. (Box 24)
  - Unsorted Subject Files
    Files consist of materials left unsorted by A. Leslie Willson, dating circa 1980s-2007. Contents relating to Dimension include texts, with author and translator correspondence; materials relating to special issues; and unsolicited contributions. Other contents relate to Willson's professional and personal correspondence, teaching, and work in professional organizations, including materials relating to the American Translators Association, the German Summer School in Taos, visiting authors at the University of Texas, and the Continuum Publishing Company's German Library series.
    - C-D (Box 24)
    - D-W (Box 25)
    - Unidentified (Box 25)
    - Unidentified (Box 26)
    - Unidentified (Box 27)
    - Unidentified (Box 28)
    - Unidentified (Box 29)
    - Unidentified (Box 30)
    - Unidentified (Box 31)
- Dimension Production Materials, Series II; 18.67; (19 boxes)
  Organized into subseries by Volume, followed by Special Issues, Microfilm, Dimension², and Unidentified.
  Production materials for each issue typically include notes, correspondence, memoranda, marked-up typescripts, pasted-up art work, mock-ups, mechanicals, galley proofs and page proofs.
  Related materials may be found in Series I, Subject Files, under names of authors and translators.
  - Volume 1
    - Number 1 (Box 32)
    - Number 2 (Box 32)
    - Number 2 (Box 33)
    - Number 3 (Box 33)
  - Volume 2
    - Number 1 (Box 33)
    - Number 2 (Box 33)
    - Number 2 (Box 34)
    - Number 3 (Box 34)
    - Number 3 (Box 35)
  - Volume 3
    - Number 1 (Box 35)
    - Number 2 (Box 35)
    - Numbers 2-3 (Box 36)
    - Number 3 (Box 36)
  - Volume 4
    - Number 1 (Box 36)
    - Number 2 (Box 36)
    - Number 2 (Box 37)
    - Number 3 (Box 37)
  - Volume 5
    - Number 1 (Box 37)
    - Number 1 (Box 38)
  - Volume 6
    - Number 1 (Box 38)
    - Number 2 (Box 38)
    - Number 3 (Box 38)
  - Volume 7
    - Number 1 (Box 38)
    - Number 1 (Box 39)
    - Number 2 (Box 39)
    - Number 3 (Box 39)
    - Number 3 (Box 40)
  - Volume 8
    - Numbers 1-2 (Box 40)
  - Volume 9
    - Number 1 (Box 40)
    - Number 2 (Box 40)
    - Number 2 (Box 41)
    - Number 3 (Box 41)
  - Volume 10
    - Numbers 1-2 (Box 41)
    - Numbers 1-2 (Box 42)
    - Number 3 (Box 42)
  - Volume 11
    - Number 1 (Box 42)
    - Number 1 (Box 43)
    - Number 2 (Box 43)
    - Number 3 (Box 43)
    - Number 3 (Box 44)
  - Volume 12
    - Number 1 (Box 44)
    - Number 3 (Box 44)
  - Volume 13
    - Number 1 (Box 44)
    - Number 1 (Box 45)
    - Number 2 (Box 46)
    - Number 3 (Box 46)
  - Volume 14
    - Unidentified numbers (Box 46)
    - Unidentified numbers (Box 47)
  - Volume 15
    - Number 1 (Box 47)
    - Number 2 (Box 47)
    - Number 3 (Box 47)
  - Volume 16
    - Number 1 (Box 47)
    - Number 2 (Box 47)
    - Number 3
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disks 12-13
  - Volume 17
    - Number 1 (Box 47)
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disks 14-15
    - Number 2 (Box 47)
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disks 16-17
    - Number 3 (Box 47)
  - Volume 18
    - Number 2 (Box 48)
    - Number 3 (Box 48)
  - Volume 19
    - Number 1 (Box 48)
    - Number 2 (Box 48)
    - Number 3 (Box 48)
  - Special issues
    - Günter Grass, 1970 (Box 48)
    - Dutch literature, 1978 (Box 48)
    - Dutch literature, 1978 (Box 49)
    - Image of America in contemporary German writing, 1983 (Box 49)
    - Liedermacher, 1991 (Box 49)
  - Microfilm
    Microfilm reproductions of Dimension (University Microfilms International) for volumes 7-11, 13-20, and a special issue on the image of American in contemporary German writing
    - Packing lists, 1979-1996 (Box 49)
    - Microfilms, 1974-1994 (Box 50)
  - Dimension²
    - Volume 2:1, 1995 (Box 49)
  - Unidentified
    - Proofs
    - Other materials